RNN을 가지고 무엇을 할 수 있습니까?
What can you do with an?
많은 것들이 있습니다.
Lots of things.
sequence의 다음 단계를 예측하는
모델을 가지고 있다고 상상해보자.
Imagine that you have a model
that predicts the next step
예를 들면,
of your sequence, for example.
당신은 sequences을 생성할 수 있습니다.
You can use that to generate sequences.
예를 들면, 텍스트, 한 시점에서의 단어 또는
한 시점에서 문자를
For example, text, either one word at
a time or one character at a time.
어느 시점(t)에서 sequence을 가지고 있으며,
RNN으로부터 예측을 생성할 수 있습니다.
For that, you take your sequence at
time, t, you generate the predictions
예측된 분포로부터 샘플링을 할 수 있습니다.
from your RNN, and then you sample
from the predicted distribution.
그것의 가능도를 기반으로 하나의 요소를 선택합니다.
And then you pick one element
based on its probability.
그리고 다음 단계의 샘플을 선택하고
계속해서 진행합니다.
And feed that sample to
the next step and go on.
반복적으로 이것을 하고 예측, 샘플링, 예측, 샘플링 ..
Do this repeatedly, predict,
sample, predict, sample, and
RNN models의 무언가로부터 매우 좋은
sequence을 생성할 수 있습니다.
you can generate a pretty good
sequence of whatever your RNN models.
더나은 결과를 얻기 위해서 더욱 정교한 방법이 있습니다.
There is a more sophisticated way to
do this, that gives better results.
모든 시점마다 다음 예측을 샘플링하기 때문에
이것은 매우 greedy(탐욕적)이다.
Because just sampling the next
prediction every time, is very greedy.
각각의 단계에서 한번 샘플링 대신에
Instead of just sampling
once at each step,
여러 시점에서 샘플링을 상상할 수 있습니다.
you could imagine
sampling multiple times.
여기서는 예를 들면 O와 A 를 선택하는 것입니다.
Here we pick O but also A for example.
우리는 여러 sequences을 가지고 있을때.
그 가정을 판정합니다.
When we have multiple sequences,
often call that hypotheses,
모든 단계에서 예측을 계속할 수 있습니다.
that you could continue
predicting from at every step.
이것들 중에서 가장 좋은 sequence을 선택할 수 있습니다.
You can choose the best sequence out
of those, by computing the total
생성되어진 모든 문자들의 전체 확률을 선택하는 방법으로..
probability of all the characters
that you generated so far.
어느 한 시점에 여러 시점의 단계에 전체 확률을 보면서.
By looking at the total probability
of the multiple time steps at a time.
선택에 위해서 우연히 만들어지는 샘플링을 방지 할 수 있습니다.
You prevent the sampling from
accidentally making one by choice, and
나쁜 결정에 의한 선택..
being stuck with that one
bad decision forever.
예를 들면, 우연히 A를 선택하면,
For example, we could have just
picked A by chance here, and
O라는 매우 합리적인 다음 단계로 이어지는 가정을 탐색하지 않습니다.
never explored the hypothesis that O
could lead to a very sensible next word.
물론, 만약 그것을 하면 우리가 고려해야 할 sequences의
수는 기하급수적으로 증가합니다.
Of course, if you do this the number
of sequences that you need to consider
grows exponentially.
그것을 하는 좀더 스마트한 방법은,
Beam Search라고 불러지는 것이 있습니다.
There is a smarter way to do that, which
is to do what's called a Beam Search.
모든 시점에서 가장 가능성있는 몇몇 후보 서열을
단지 지키고, 말하는 것입니다.
You only keep, say, the most likely few
candidate sequences at every time step,
그리고, 나머지는 단순히 제거하는 것입니다.
and then simply prune the rest.
실제적으로, 매우 좋은 sequences을 생성하도록
매우 잘 동작합니다.
In practice, this works very well for
generating very good
sequences from your model.